That
[music]
City Situations is our second video and
if you also want to understand what health
insurance is, then before that you
must watch video number one, so let's talk about what
things you should keep in mind while taking health insurance and
what are those things that you should definitely
check once, so that when you are admitted to the hospital and
in case of emergency,
you do not have to spend a lot of money, to
avoid this it becomes
very important for you to understand these points, the first thing is that
whenever you are buying an insurance policy, then
definitely see what is the rate of that
insurance company's claim process, it does
not take much time, it is
not very Delhi-ites,
you should keep this in mind because when you are
admitted to the hospital, if
you do not get clearance in it, then it becomes a
big worry for you and a big problem for your family,
so
such insurance companies should have
very good customer care support, its time
processing skills, racing car
process, it should be very fast,
secondly, always use a family floater policy, you
can buy a private policy, if you
are alone then definitely you should buy a  You should buy a policy for yourself
but if you live with your family
then definitely you should
buy a policy for the entire family, the
benefit of this is that
all the people become immortal in one policy, if you
do it on individual premium then it will be very
high and when you
take one premium and one policy for the entire family together
then it costs less on your pocket
and see all the people never fall sick together, if there is a
death in one family then the
entire expenditure on it can be incurred there only
or the distributor will
reduce it a little, the child amount can be spent
on the rest of the family members as per the need,
so always go for a family floater
policy, the third most important thing is
that the premium amount of insurance which you pay to the insurance
company and Jasmin leaves,
understand that there is a demand, which insurance company
gives quality, policy command,
how much amount the insurance company guarantees for your expenses,
so select it very
carefully, this is also a big thing of love, the
Ministry of Delhi has said that it has to fall on your pocket many
times and that much MS Word wishes  If
you need it, you may face problems or have to
spend money from outside, then
definitely take a balanced approach and
keep the premium as much as you can easily afford.
How many people are there in your policy
and how much they may need, if you respect it then you may
definitely need more, so
make this calculation as well. This is
also a very important point
for buying such an insurance policy.
Apart from this, also keep in mind whether your nearest
hospital or any 6 hospitals are
in the cashless network of that insurance company or not. Because it should not happen that
you have bought the policy but in an emergency, you
go to the school and get admitted, but it is
not in the cashless network of that company, then
you will have to spend all the money on the chair in the hospital.
Then you will have to send this to the insurance company
for 10 minutes, which is a long
process, although in Uttar Pradesh it takes
you one and a half to two months, you will have to fill the claim form, there are
many things, so it is
better that you have such a policy that has a
large network of network hospitals, so there is a hospital near you
where you can go for queries, it is
not possible.  Maternity benefit:
Understand maternity benefit. Are the benefits related to pregnancy and delivery
covered? But
many insurance companies do
not provide this coverage in retail policies.
Now, there are many players who
provide you with death and maternity benefits. So,
if you are getting married or planning a child, then
you should definitely take a policy in
which you get maternity benefits. There is a
waiting period of one or two years along with the hassle and it is good for you.
Although all the insurance companies
provide prevent hospitalization coverage, but still
you should check in your policy
whether it is
providing you coverage for hospitalization or not.
Complete hospitalization and post hospitalization
means that when you are admitted in the hospital
and you are treated and you get the
claim from the insurance or you get it
cashless, then all the
expenses incurred generally 30 days before hospitalization and generally seven days after discharge from the hospital, whether it is doctor
's fees or anything else, are covered.  The
insurance company subsidizes all the expenses you have incurred on medicines,
for that you have to fill the claim form again
and then
send it to your insurance company, for that
I will make a separate video in detail about
how you can get reimbursement, you
can prefer that, nowadays when many
insurance companies buy an appointment policy
then they also give you this daily health checkup line
along with it, although it does
not have a big impact on the premium, but if by
going through it you get a small amount of expenses throughout the year, then
daily essence is
beneficial for both you and the company, you can read whether
any disease is going to come
and you can take the right decision in time and can
avoid the upcoming danger, so
use such plans in that the health
checkup benefits given to you by the insurance company is
a big pain point, now
in the weight of our customers and patients,
when we get
admitted in the hospital, the hospital is
asking for some money from us, there are some reasons for this, so
you should carefully check the key in your policy and close the
typing key.  No,
copper means that whatever the hospital
expenses are, the insurance company expects to pass on one percent of the value, i.e. 5
percent, to the
group customer. So, if it is
written somewhere in the policy, then
check it because it will be a burden on your pocket. The
answer is this cashless hospital insurance process. When you go to avail these
benefits, it is typing that
a cap has been imposed on a particular disease
and for example, we were taking the example of cutter letter
G. So, it is possible that the insurance company will deduct
₹3000 for cataract surgery and will
fix this period. But if you
go to such a hospital and the expense is ₹50,000, then
you may have to spend ₹20,000 because there is a
tap installed there. So,
you should check this thing in the policy now so that there is no
confusion later on and you do not get a bad omen or shock as to
why I had to do this.
Apart from this, a big mistake that
customers make is not disclosing the pre-existing business.
In most of the light policies, there is a waiting period of
so many days.  After this, if your pre-existing disease is
discovered, then it is better that you
give correct information to the insurance company
because if your doctor has put those information
in your file and it goes to the insurance company, then
you will not get money even for this disease which
you actually suffered
just because you had hidden some information.
If you had a disease and had
not disclosed it, then it is
more beneficial in being transparent. This disease or
some other meeting will be covered after some time period. If
you check that the coverage is there in your policy, it would be
better if you
issue such policies in which
pre-existing disease is discovered
after some time period, say one year, two years, four or
five years. This is a very important point
and the biggest point on which generally there are
fights between patients and hospital staff in the hospital is 'Have no
medical expenses' or non-verbal items
of the customer, so I had questions about the policy. I
went to the hospital but if the
insurance company did not disclose this amount, then you will have to pay
and this pack has many such  Consumables are
disposable items which are
not coated with iodine on this update, the
hospital code is not at fault in that, the
insurance company from the hospital says
that you have to collect this point from the patient
but this can also be filled in the policy in advance,
if there is any such point in your policy
that you are not paying any price
then definitely you do not have to do anything, so
you can also check such polythene, here there should
not be any obligation on you to pay the bill on non, this is a very important thing, so
if you keep these points in mind and
if you buy the policy then you will not face any big problem, you will not face
any shock, if any of
your family members will be admitted to the hospital for cashless policy, then
definitely give it to them carefully this time
and share this video with as many
people as possible so that the money gets benefited
and if you have come to the channel for the first time then
definitely subscribe and also press the bell icon button
108 so that
you keep getting such informative videos on time, thank you